<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorials on Yuan Meng</title>
    <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/categories/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorials on Yuan Meng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Yuan Meng</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.yuan-meng.com/categories/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Teaching A Peceptron to See</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/perceptron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/perceptron/</guid>
      <description>Ten years after the ImageNet Challenge thawed the last AI winter, ChaptGPT and generative AI have become part of our everyday life and colloquial language, like (almost) no one has imagined just 2 years back. As increasingly more folks aspire to foray into the field of ML/AI, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think about a lesson from my guitar teacher:
 Everyone wants to start playing the songs they love right off the bat, but without nailing seemingly &amp;ldquo;boring&amp;rdquo; building blocks such as scales, harmonies, and rhythms, the songs you love will sound like a nightmare&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code ML Algorithms From Scratch</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/md_coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/md_coding/</guid>
      <description>Coding interviews can mean different things for &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; software engineers (back-end, front-end, full-stack, etc.) and engineers with a machine learning focus. Apart from LeetCode-style questions, ML engineers (as well as applied scientists, research engineers, and, occasionally, machine learning data scientists) may be asked to implement a classic ML algorithm from scratch during an interview.
This may sound scary if you&amp;rsquo;ve only used libraries to train models without understanding how learning algorithms work under the hood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Up Python Environment for CogSci 131</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/python_env/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/python_env/</guid>
      <description>CogSci 131 (Computational Modeling of Cognition) is one of my favorite classes at Berkeley when I took it with Prof. Tom Griffiths in 2016. Now I&amp;rsquo;m teaching it in my last semester. Before getting to the fun parts (e.g., implementing recurrent nets and classic RL algorithms like SARSA using vanilla NumPy), one needs to set up the right Python environment. I hope this tutorial can save students some headaches.
Option #1: Conda Virtual Environment To avoid nightmares down the line👇, use virtual environments for your local stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Minimalist Setup for Zoom Guitar Lessons</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/guitar/</guid>
      <description>Goals + Overview (macOS) I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking guitar lessons over Zoom since the pandemic. As an electric player, I initially found it challenging to split audio inputs/outputs multiple ways:
 Input #1: Microphone &amp;ndash; so I can talk to my teacher Input #2: Guitar &amp;ndash; no need to explain 🎸🤟 :) Output #1: Headphone &amp;ndash; so I hear guitar effects created by my amp simulator Output #2: Zoom &amp;ndash; so my teacher hears the same effects, not just dry signals  After some research, I found a setup that feels simple and intuitive to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal Inference in Data Science</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/causality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/causality/</guid>
      <description>What do you see? 👀
 You&amp;rsquo;re probably thinking, &amp;ldquo;The red block stopped, right after which the green block started to move coincidentally.&amp;quot;
Nice try&amp;hellip; I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking, &amp;ldquo;The red block made the green one move&amp;rdquo;.
Why Ask Why? We can&amp;rsquo;t help but think about causation Your stats professor can say &amp;ldquo;correlation is not causation&amp;rdquo; like a broken record, but we can&amp;rsquo;t help but think about causation. Even 12-month-old babies don&amp;rsquo;t think the motions of the two blocks are merely correlated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing Metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/metrics/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Tis the college and job application season of the year. If only schools and companies have crystal balls to see into each candidate&amp;rsquo;s future achievements, they need not interview people; since they do not have such things, SAT scores, GPA, internships, and other quantifiable metrics are used to aid decisions. Simplified metrics are by no means ideal — As Goodhart put it (often paraphrased), &amp;ldquo;When a measure becomes a metric, it ceases to be a good measure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
