<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Yuan Meng</title>
    <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Yuan Meng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Yuan Meng</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Minimalist Setup for Zoom Guitar Lessons</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/guitar/</guid>
      <description> Pain point
 Things you need  A guitar   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quasi-Experiments for Causal Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/causality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/causality/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Causation [&amp;hellip;] is the cement of the universe.&amp;rdquo; — David Hume, Abstract
 Data scientists help the team make good decisions and good decisions rely on causation. Prof. Alison Gopnik always has the nicest example: While yellow fingers and smoking are both correlated with lung cancer, washing hands doesn&amp;rsquo;t prevent cancer.
Randomized controlled experiments, or A/B tests, are the gold standard for establishing causality. Unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s not always possible, feasible, or ethical to randomly assign people into different variants: In the example above, you can&amp;rsquo;t in good conscience force someone to smoke, nor can you easily have them quit smoking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest Hits in Cognitively Inpsired AI</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/cocosci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/cocosci/</guid>
      <description>This paper collection reflects some of the most exiting trends in computational cognitive science and cognitively inspired AI, in my opinion.
 Overview How can AI and cognitive science shed light on each other&amp;rsquo;s biggest challenges?
 Lake, B. M., Ullman, T. D., Tenenbaum, J. B., &amp;amp; Gershman, S. J. (2017). Building machines that learn and think like people. Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 40. (PDF) Ullman, T. D., &amp;amp; Tenenbaum, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing Metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/metrics/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Tis the college and job application season of the year. If only schools and companies have crystal balls to see into each candidate&amp;rsquo;s future achievements, they need not interview people; since they do not have such things, SAT scores, GPA, internships, and other quantifiable metrics are used to aid decisions. Simplified metrics are by no means ideal — As Goodhart put it (often paraphrased), &amp;ldquo;When a measure becomes a metric, it ceases to be a good measure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
