<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yuan Meng</title>
    <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yuan Meng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Yuan Meng</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.yuan-meng.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Evolution of Learning to Rank</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/ltr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/ltr/</guid>
      <description>First Thing First  Enigmas of the universe  Cannot be known without a search  &amp;mdash; Epica, Omega (2021)
 In The Rainmaker (1997), the freshly graduated lawyer Rudy Baylor faced off against a giant insurance firm in his debut case, almost getting buried by mountains of case files that the corporate lawyers never expected him to sift through. If only Rudy had a search engine that retrieves all files mentioning suspicious denials and ranks them from most to least relevant, the case prep would&amp;rsquo;ve been a breeze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autocompletion for Search Enginees</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/autocomplete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/autocomplete/</guid>
      <description>Autocompletion dates back half a century ago (Longuet-Higgins &amp;amp; Ortony, 1968), initially designed to save keystrokes as people type and help those with physical disabilities type faster. The incomplete user input is the &amp;ldquo;query prefix&amp;rdquo; and suggested ways of extending the prefix into a full query are &amp;ldquo;query completions&amp;rdquo;. This feature is essential to modern text editors and search engines.
 This blog post summarizes key ideas from the survey paper A Survey of Query Auto Completion in Information Retrieval, recommended by my Search teammate at DoorDash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching A Peceptron to See</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/perceptron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/perceptron/</guid>
      <description>Ten years after the ImageNet Challenge thawed the last AI winter, ChaptGPT and generative AI have become part of our everyday life and colloquial language, like (almost) no one has imagined just 2 years back. As increasingly more folks aspire to foray into the field of ML/AI, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think about a lesson from my guitar teacher:
 Everyone wants to start playing the songs they love right off the bat, but without nailing seemingly &amp;ldquo;boring&amp;rdquo; building blocks such as scales, harmonies, and rhythms, the songs you love will sound like a nightmare&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brithday Wish</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/birthday/</guid>
      <description>Survival was the theme of this past year. When I expressed layoff worries in February 2022 (after Googling consequences of interest rate hikes as an econ noob&amp;hellip;), friends joked that I was a &amp;ldquo;Golden State Worrier&amp;rdquo;. After the chips were down last November, the shock was not one bit absorbed by anticipation. Seeing coworkers I just spoke and worked side by side with disappearing was unreal and painful. Since then I can&amp;rsquo;t quite recall the last time I felt truly exited or relaxed &amp;mdash; I seem to overdo what I can to feel a tiny bit safer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code ML Algorithms From Scratch</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/md_coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/md_coding/</guid>
      <description>Coding interviews can mean different things for &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; software engineers (back-end, front-end, full-stack, etc.) and engineers with a machine learning focus. Apart from LeetCode-style questions, ML engineers (as well as applied scientists, research engineers, and, occasionally, machine learning data scientists) may be asked to implement a classic ML algorithm from scratch during an interview.
This may sound scary if you&amp;rsquo;ve only used libraries to train models without understanding how learning algorithms work under the hood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Could Anyone Know How Another Feels?</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/empathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/empathy/</guid>
      <description>The thought of my family&amp;rsquo;s graves  Was the only moment  I used to experience true love  That love remains infinite  As I&amp;rsquo;ll never be the man my father is 
How can you &amp;ldquo;just be yourself&amp;rdquo;  When you don&amp;rsquo;t know who you are?  Stop saying &amp;ldquo;I know how you feel&amp;rdquo;  How could anyone know how another feels?  &amp;mdash; Nightwish, Song of Myself (2011)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Quirky) Roadmap for New Grad Data Scientists</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/newgrads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/newgrads/</guid>
      <description>New Grad Timeline Since last November, I regularly get questions about how to get data science jobs. I&amp;rsquo;ve hesitated to give advice because no advice applies to everyone. As more people ask, however, I want to write a post for those in my shoes:
 (PhD) students applying to machine learning or product data scientist roles at tech companies through university recruiting.
 What&amp;rsquo;s special about university recruiting  July to October is high time to start: Some say companies have more headcounts at the beginning of each year &amp;mdash; that&amp;rsquo;s just not true for university recruiting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ph.D. Grind: Doing Nothing Is the Hardest Thing</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/nothingness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/nothingness/</guid>
      <description>Seriously, Read The Ph.D. Grind Everyone doing a Ph.D. or considering doing one should read The Ph.D. Grind. Don&amp;rsquo;t wait &amp;mdash; you&amp;rsquo;ll learn the much-needed &amp;ldquo;rational optimism&amp;rdquo; for this crazy ride.
I only came across this gem in my final semester year of Ph.D. but Dr. Philip Guo&amp;rsquo;s reflections of his first year in grad school immediately resonated with my own. I, too, procrastinated heavily for the first time in my life and felt I somehow lost my sense of direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Up Python Environment for CogSci 131</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/python_env/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/python_env/</guid>
      <description>CogSci 131 (Computational Modeling of Cognition) is one of my favorite classes at Berkeley when I took it with Prof. Tom Griffiths in 2016. Now I&amp;rsquo;m teaching it in my last semester. Before getting to the fun parts (e.g., implementing recurrent nets and classic RL algorithms like SARSA using vanilla NumPy), one needs to set up the right Python environment. I hope this tutorial can save students some headaches.
Option #1: Conda Virtual Environment To avoid nightmares down the line👇, use virtual environments for your local stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year Resolutions</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/resolutions-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/resolutions-2022/</guid>
      <description>Piled Higher and Deeper: https://phdcomics.com/comics.php?f=1670
  Resolutions are meant to be broken, but like everything good in life, it&amp;rsquo;s better to try and fail than never to have attempted at all. So here&amp;rsquo;s my attempt for 2022.
1. Be a better modeler 2021 felt quite surreal &amp;mdash; I got my first job offer as a machine learning data scientist, something I&amp;rsquo;d been dreaming of for nearly two years. In 2022, I wanna up my ante in the modeling game by working through (a subset of) the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Minimalist Setup for Zoom Guitar Lessons</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/guitar/</guid>
      <description>Goals + Overview (macOS) I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking guitar lessons over Zoom since the pandemic. As an electric player, I initially found it challenging to split audio inputs/outputs multiple ways:
 Input #1: Microphone &amp;ndash; so I can talk to my teacher Input #2: Guitar &amp;ndash; no need to explain 🎸🤟 :) Output #1: Headphone &amp;ndash; so I hear guitar effects created by my amp simulator Output #2: Zoom &amp;ndash; so my teacher hears the same effects, not just dry signals  After some research, I found a setup that feels simple and intuitive to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal Inference in Data Science</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/causality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/causality/</guid>
      <description>What do you see? 👀
 You&amp;rsquo;re probably thinking, &amp;ldquo;The red block stopped, right after which the green block started to move coincidentally.&amp;quot;
Nice try&amp;hellip; I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking, &amp;ldquo;The red block made the green one move&amp;rdquo;.
Why Ask Why? We can&amp;rsquo;t help but think about causation Your stats professor can say &amp;ldquo;correlation is not causation&amp;rdquo; like a broken record, but we can&amp;rsquo;t help but think about causation. Even 12-month-old babies don&amp;rsquo;t think the motions of the two blocks are merely correlated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest Hits in Cognitively Inpsired AI</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/cocosci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/cocosci/</guid>
      <description>This paper collection reflects some of the most exiting trends in computational cognitive science and cognitively inspired AI, in my opinion.
 Overview How can AI and cognitive science shed light on each other&amp;rsquo;s biggest challenges?
 Lake, B. M., Ullman, T. D., Tenenbaum, J. B., &amp;amp; Gershman, S. J. (2017). Building machines that learn and think like people. Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 40. (PDF) Ullman, T. D., &amp;amp; Tenenbaum, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing Metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/metrics/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Tis the college and job application season of the year. If only schools and companies have crystal balls to see into each candidate&amp;rsquo;s future achievements, they need not interview people; since they do not have such things, SAT scores, GPA, internships, and other quantifiable metrics are used to aid decisions. Simplified metrics are by no means ideal — As Goodhart put it (often paraphrased), &amp;ldquo;When a measure becomes a metric, it ceases to be a good measure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
