<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on Yuan Meng</title>
    <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on Yuan Meng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Yuan Meng</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.yuan-meng.com/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(Opinionated) Guide to ML Engineer Job Hunting</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/mle_interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/mle_interviews/</guid>
      <description>The Marriage Analogy Nearly 2 years ago, I wrote a blog post on how to find jobs as a new grad data scientist (as a twist of fate, I never worked as a product data scientist but instead became an ML engineer at DoorDash). Back in 2021, I cared a ton about interview skills, answer &amp;ldquo;frameworks&amp;rdquo;, and whatnot, which may still come handy at New Grad or Early Career levels. For experienced hires, however, I think of interviews as some sort of marriage proposal &amp;mdash; it&amp;rsquo;s something you can rehearse but can never force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Quirky) Roadmap for New Grad Data Scientists</title>
      <link>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/newgrads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yuan-meng.com/posts/newgrads/</guid>
      <description>New Grad Timeline Since last November, I regularly get questions about how to get data science jobs. I&amp;rsquo;ve hesitated to give advice because no advice applies to everyone. As more people ask, however, I want to write a post for those in my shoes:
 (PhD) students applying to machine learning or product data scientist roles at tech companies through university recruiting.
 What&amp;rsquo;s special about university recruiting  July to October is high time to start: Some say companies have more headcounts at the beginning of each year &amp;mdash; that&amp;rsquo;s just not true for university recruiting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
